# ALMAR HEIMIR JÓHANNSSON

Phone: (354) 690-1102 Sæmundargata 20, apartment 220

Ahj26@hi.is Reykjavik, 102

### **ABOUT ME**

My name is Almar Heimir Jóhannsson, I'm 22 years old and grew up in Akureyri in the northern part of Iceland. I spent a big part of my childhood on a farm, doing all kinds of farming jobs and I have worked most of my life with school. Currently studying Industrial Engineering at the University of Iceland and will graduate in the spring of 2023. My hobbies include coding, solutions and, I'm an avid sports fan.

#### **EDUCATION**

BS	University of Iceland, Industrial Engineering	May 2023
JC	Akureyri Junior College, Natural Sciences	June 2019

### **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

### University of Iceland, Reykjavik

January 2023 to May 2023

Teacher, Faculty of Industrial Engineering, Mechanical Engineering and Computer Science

I am going to teach Operational Research, an undergraduate course averaging 70 students per semester, covering the following topics: Data wrangling, Simplex, Dual solution, Graph optimization, Sensitivity analysis, Real world examples of Operational Research

- Around six hours of lectures every week with a problem-based learning model.
- Developing quizzes, exams, and homework.
- Revising the syllabus to meet accreditation standards
- Coordinate grading with a professor of the department

University of Iceland, Reykjavik August 2022 to December 2022 **Teaching Assistant**, Faculty of Industrial Engineering, Mechanical Engineering and Computer Science

The fall semester of 2022 I helped the Operational Research professors revising the syllabus to meet accreditation standards and coordinated grading with a professor of the department.

### University of Iceland, Reykjavik

August 2022 to December 2022

Teaching Assistant, Faculty of Industrial Engineering, Mechanical Engineering and Computer Science

I held weekly classes for 35 students in Computer Science 1, where we went more in depth into material if needed, went over the problem sheet and helped the students in any way I could. I also graded their weekly assignments as well as I helped grade the midterm exam.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **As Styrktarfelag** Reykjavik **Staff and Support representative,** As Klukkuvellir

May 2021 to September 2022

As is a home for disabled people and focuses on independent living for these individuals.

- I helped helping the people with their daily affairs such as financial help, cooking or simply talking to them.
- Learned a great deal from these the residents and gained an understanding of working with different types of people.
- Learned a great deal about myself. The job really opened my eyes for my love of teaching and helping others understanding a concept.

**Hotel KEX** Reykjavik **Head Chef,** Kex restaurant

June 2020 to September 2020

In the summer of 2020 I, became the head chef at Kex Hotel in Reykjavik, Iceland.

- I cooked, ordered supplies, made drinks, cleaned the kitchen/bar
- Had great feedback both from customers as well as the people who owned the restaurant

### **PROFESSIONAL TRAINING**

## Working machine Certification, Labor Office of Iceland, 2017

Certified to work on small excavators, forklifts, tractors, and small cranes.

### **COMMUNITY SERVICE**

### **Knattspyrnufélag Akureyrar** (Local sports club in Akureyri, Iceland)

Volunteer work for my local and community sports club in Akureyri, Iceland.

Volunteer work at games and helping to set up events. Refereed the kid games in both soccer and group handball.

#### LANGUAGES

**Icelandic**: Native Language

English: Superior Listener, Advanced Speaker, Superior Reading and Writing

**Danish:** Intermediate Listener, Novice Speaker, Advanced Reading and Writing

**Spanish**: Novice Listener, Novice Speaker, Novice Reading and Writing

### **COMPUTER SKILLS**

**Programming**: C++, Java, Python, SQL, Html, CSS, Javascript

**Applications**: Visual Studio, IntelliJ, Matlab, SQLite, Autocad, Inventor, Fusion 360

Platforms: Windows, Ubuntu Linux, Kali Linux, OS

### **OTHER**

# The Engineering Design competition of the University of Iceland 2023

**Head of the Competition,** Faculty of Industrial Engineering, Mechanical Engineering and Computer Science

I am leading the Engineering Design Competition this year where students and faculty will challenge each other designing a robot that needs to complete an obstacle course. My duties include:

- Designing the course and challenges
- Talking to UT Messan, the conference where the competition will be held in Harpa Conference Hall in February 2023
- Interfacing with Harpa Conference Hall regarding access to the building and set up time for the course
- Liasing with and supporting competitors as well managing the registrations
- Liasing with the sponsors who have given us around \$10,000 to distribute as prize money.

Icelandic Citizenship

#### REFERENCES

### Dr. Tómas Philip Rúnarsson, Professor of Industrial Engineering

Faculty of Industrial Engineering, Mechanical Engineering and Computer Science University of Iceland

Sæmundargata 2, 102 Reykjavík

Phone: +354 525 4733 Email: tpr@hi.is

### Dr. Guðmundur Valur Oddsson, Head of Industrial Engineering Faculty

Faculty of Industrial Engineering, Mechanical Engineering and Computer Science University of Iceland

Sæmundargata 2, 102 Reykjavík

Phone: +354 525 4635 Email: gvo@hi.is

# Ms Ásta Hrönn Ingvarsdóttir, Head of As Klukkuvellir

As Klukkuvellir As Styrkingarfelag Klukkuvellir 12, 220 Hafnarfjordur

Phone: +354 551 3700 Email: asta@styrktarfelag.is